Kishan Rasikbhai Akbari

+91 709-202-9994

kishanakbari@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/kishan-rasikbhai-akbari/ • https://github.com/kishanAk21

OBJECTIVE

An engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the IT/Mechanical/Aerospace industry. In my professional career I have worked with some of the top engineering firms. Currently, I am exploring the field of Artificial Intelligent (AI) and Machine Learning (ML) and looking forward to implement it to solve the real world challenges.

EDUCATION

Master's Degree in Mechanical Engineering

Jul 2015 - Jul 2017

Indian Institute of Technology Madras, Chennai

Bachelor's Degree in Mechanical Engineering

Jun 2011 - Jul 2015

Faculty of Technology and Engineering, Maharaja Sayajirao University of Baroda, Vadodara

SKILLS

Programming: Python, SQL, MATLAB

Data Tools/Techniques: MS Excel, Tableau, Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA), ML, DL, NLP

CAD packages: Solidworks, Auto CAD, Creo Parametric, CADfix

Simulation/Tools: COMSOL Multiphysics, ANSYS, SC03, Siemens NX, Abaqus

Documentation: MS Office, LATEX

WORK EXPERIENCE

Engineering Lead

Jan 2021 - Present

Infosys Ltd • Bangalore

- FE modelling and analysis of Gas Turbine Engine externals components.
- Working on the development of pipes damping prediction models using statistical techniques.

Advanced Stress Engineer

Sep 2019 - Dec 2020

Rolls-Royce India Pvt Ltd • Bangalore

- Worked on FEA modelling and Stress analysis of Gas turbine Engine combustor components.
- Contributed to the combustor tiles casting defects data analysis and classification project. Worked on defect data exploration (EDA) and developed go/no-go classifier.

Component Engineer Mechanical Analyst

Feb 2019 - Sep 2019

Rolls-Royce India Pvt Ltd • Bangalore

- Contributed to the development of on-fleet repair documents for mechanical components of Gas Turbine Engine.
- Supported design and optimisation of mechanical components for Gas Turbine Engine.

Engineering Graduate

Jul 2017 - Jan 2019

Rolls-Royce India Pvt Ltd • Bangalore

- Developed and implemented metal surface defect image classification models using Deep leaning CNN techniques.
- Investigated the testing failure of gas turbine engine and proved the hypothesis behind the problem.
- Contributed to the development of automatic calculation tool as a part of process improvement initiative.

COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

Engineering Mathematics

Probability and Statistics

Computational Methods

- Importing & Cleaning Data with Python (DataCamp)
- Data Manipulation with Python (DataCamp)
- Data Visualisation with Python (DataCamp)

PROJECTS

Data Science Repository

 Developed a GitHub repository which includes various kind of data science problems solved using different statistical and ML techniques. This repository is a personal project for educational purpose.

Quantitative Non-Destructive Testing of Metal Thermal Barrier Coating

• This project covers implementation of infrared thermography for structural health monitoring of thermal barrier coatings used in aerospace applications.

AWARDS AND HONOURS

Rolls-Royce Silver Award

2019

Received prestigious Rolls-Royce Silver Award for aero engine compressor blades lifing work.

University Gold Medal

2015

 Awarded Gold Medal for excellent achievement in the Design of Machine Element course from M.S. University.

ABB JDF Scholarship

2012

• Awarded ABB JDF scholarship for exceptional academic as well as extra-curricular record.